JOHN FLETCHER

CONTACT

2

260 Summit Blvd, Broomfield, Colorado 80021



(831)261-1452

Y

johnfletcher831@gmail.com

SKILLS

Backend:

- Java
- Spring Boot
- Webflux
- RabbitMQ
- Axon
- REST

Frontend:

- React
- React Native
- HTML/CSS
- Javascript

Infrastructure:

- AWS
- Docker

PERSONAL

- Private Helicopter Pilot
- Certified SCUBA Diver

An energetic software engineer with years of experience developing and implementing customer focused solutions. A hard working engineer with variety of professional experiences as well as personal projects that cover a variety of technical applications. Excellent critical thinking and time management skills with the ability to think outside the box.

EXPERIENCE

March 2023 - Current

Co-Founder Knowhere, Boulder, CO

Founded, designed, developed, and distributed Knowhere: A social platform that allows businesses to promote their day to day experiences directly to customers. In turn, users can easily discover, plan, and attend local events with friends.

- Developed a Spring microservice architecture hosted on AWS
- Created 2 react-native mobile app clients for both businesses and users (Available on App Store)
- 83,000 lines of code in Spring and React Native
- Integrated with monitoring tools such as DataDog, Snyk, Sentry, and PagerDuty

July 2022 - Current

Software Engineer 2 Garmin, Boulder, CO

Working on the Garmin Pay platform team to provide scalable and efficient micro services in order to bring the best experience to our customers.

- Integrated push provisioning capability into Garmin Pay's existing API to allow customers to directly add credit/debit cards onto their Garmin device
- Worked with Visa, Discover, Mastercard software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet requirements for functionality and scalability
- Helped implement new front-end reactive microservice that 2x original performance with Webflux
- Took initiative in creating new Spring Boot microservice that required Axon, RabbitMQ, Spring Security, and other technologies
- Reduced Warning logs by 5% as personal project

May 2018 - August 2018

System Engineer Intern NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory

Worked on the proposed Mars Sample Return mission to collect and return Martian dust back to Earth.

- Created model to show possibility of Martian dust particle reaching Earth's Biosphere
- Developed MATLAB software to quicken dust propagation simulations by 60%
- Presented project's model to Mars Exploration Directorate

EDUCATION

May 2022

Bachelor of Science Computer Science (Major GPA: 3.840) University of Colorado Boulder, Boulder, CO

Relevant completed courses: Data Structures, Computer Systems, Principles of Programming Languages, Discrete Math, Software Development